Biswajit Pandey (1) Featured

Java and Full Stack Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Coding, Debugging, Solution Optimization, Project Execution, Project Planning, Team Building, Requirement Gathering and Software Design



Current Designation: IT Analyst Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore,Kolkata,Hyderabad

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Core Java, J2EE, React. js, Full Stack Development, Coding, Debugging, Solution Optimization, Project Execution, Project Planning, Team Building, Requirement Gathering, Software Design

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Summary

An enthusiastic professional with nearly 9 years of rich and extensive experience in Software Application Development (Core Java and Full Stack)

Provided insightful knowledge of business process analysis (As-Is, To-Be) and design; managed application based process reengineering as well as process customization, process optimization and provided technical solutions from stability prospective Expertise & hands on experience in Core Java, Web development-J2EE, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring Data, Microservices, React.js, HTML, JavaScript, Database (Oracle SQL and MySQL) and JMS.

Completed certification in Oracle Certified Java Programmer (OCPJP Java SE 6).

Identified, conceptualized and documented appropriate technical solution approaches for various business scenarios and challenges.

Work Experience

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. as IT Analyst

May 2017 to Till Date

Developed multiple applications for JP Morgan Chase and MetLife using technologies such as Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Struts 1.1, Core Java, React.js, AWS, JSP and MS-SQL.

Enhanced FX Payments Manager module, Global Insurance Sales Platform and Credit Life Admin System.

Designed solutions conforming to architectural requirements such as scalability, maintainability, reliability, usability and security; fixed defects as the code was promoted to higher environments.

Managed client/user interaction for requirement gathering, risk assessment, finalization of technical specifications and discussed for effort/cost/time estimation.

Delivered accurate estimated development times; developed new functionalities, both back-end and front-end.

HCL Technologies as Tech Lead

Nov 2016 to May 2017

Played a major role in Cisco Network Engineering talent acquisition and was a part of Cisco resource pool for enhancement of skills.

Participated in recruitment drives.

Ericsson India Global Services Pvt. Ltd. as Engineer

Dec 2011 to Nov 2016

Designed and built multiple applications using Core Java, Struts 1.1 and VBA (Macro for excel).

Assisted updates to the management on work in progress, work completed, work planned, and issues that potentially impacted the on time completion or quality of work.

Developed new applications, components & added functionality to existing systems.

Created Market Orders for Alcatel-Lucent along with network capacity analysis for Sprint, US.

Visual Basic Automation for process automation and reducing manual effort.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Dream Institute of Technology, West Bengal University of Technology in 2011

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Oracle Certified Java Programmer (OCPJP Java SE 6)

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
J2EE		2020	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
MySQL		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Spring	5	2020	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Hibernate	4	2019	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
CORE JAVA	1.8	2020	8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
React.js	15	2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Bengali	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Job Type: Permanent

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

Work Authorization